Juncheng (Billy) Li

—



+1 (412) 999 5427



junchenl@andrew.cmu.edu lijuncheng16@gmail.com



https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=fBnAdlkAAAAJ

ABOUT ME

"With multi-disciplinary knowledge background and a clear focus on robust deep learning in multi-modal machine learning, I have prepared myself to delve into more challenging research problems, solve them and create something of value to the real-world!"

RESEARCH INTEREST

- # Robust Deep Learning # Multimodal Machine
- Learning
- # Natural language Processing
- # Audio / Speech Processing

Reviewer

ICML 20-22, NeurIPS 20-22, ICLR 2022, AAAI 20/21, CVPR 20-22, ACL 21/22 IEEE TALLIP, IEEE TNNLS

Teaching

11-751 Speech Recognition; 15-640 Distributed Stystem; Mentoring Undergrads. Page 1/2

WORK EXPERIENCE —

Quantative Research Consultant

Two Sigma Investment LLC

May 2022 - Aug 2022 | New York, NY

- Curate evaluations and/or scoring of audio/video/imagery data, particularly those with economic meaning
- Deep Learning Research Engineer
 Bosch Center for Artificial Intelligence

Jul 2018 - Sept 2019 | Pittsburgh, PA

- Applied robust machine learning algorithms to Bosch Autonomous driving project, improved system robustness by 50% in bad weather condition.
- Explored mulimodality embeddings to make use of multi-sensor input, transferred the technology to Bosch business team.
- Developed occupancy detection solution using RGB-D sensor, and facilitated the transfer of technology to business unit.
- Applied representation learning to Bosch drier, improved energy efficiency by 5%.
- Generated 2 patents and top-tier AI conference publications.
- Mentored 2 interns and hired 5 members for the new team.

• Research Engineer

Bosch Research and Technology Center

Apr 2015 - June 2018 | Pittsburgh, PA

- Designed, Developed, and tested a 3D visualization platform based on BIM (Building Information Model) for Smart Campus sensor network (MQTT protocol) using Java at backend and Javascript at frontend.
- Collaborated closely with Bosch Next App development team, developed VR indoor navigation solution, and deployed the Bosch Next APP on App Store.
- Applied sound recognition to manufactoring production line to detect potential anomaly thus reducing the overall downtime by 10%.
- Applied sound recognition to detect leak in water pipelines, generated 1 patent.

EDUCATION

PHD Candidate (Language Technology Institute)
 School of Computer Science, Carnegie Mellon University

2017 - Present (expected May 2023) | Pittsburgh, PA

Dual Degree Master of Science (Advanced Infrastructure
 System + Engineering Technology Innovation & Management)
 Carnegie Mellon University

2012 - 2015 | Pittsburgh, PA

 Bachelor of Science in Structural Engineering Tongji University

2008 - 2012 | Shanghai, China

Exchange Student in Computational Earthquake Design
 National Chengkung University

2012 | Tainan, Taiwan

COURSE

NLP & Deep Learning

- # Neural Networks for NLP
- # Neural Machine Translation
- # Deep Reinforcement Learning
- # Speech Recognition
- # Algorithm for NLP
- # Large Scale MultiMedia Analysis
- # Machine Learning
- # Statistical Machine Learning
- # Convex Optimization

Programming

- # Distributed System
- # Software Engineering
- # Algorithm Design and Analysis
- # Computer Networks
- # Parallel and Sequential Data
- Structures and Algorithms
- # Introductory to Computer
- System(C) # Machine Learning
- # Principles of O-O Programming
- # Data Mining
- # Rapid Prototyping(JAVA)
- # Numerical Methods
- # Data acquisition
- # Data Management.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

 Java
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

 Python
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

 C / C++
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

 JS/ HTML / CSS
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

 Swift
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

 MatLab
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

LANGUAGE SKILLS

 Chinese
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

 English
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

 Japanese
 ♦ ♦ ♦ ♦

PUBLICATIONS (citations: 1251, h-index: 14) —

♦ Very Deep Convolutional Neural Networks for Raw Waveforms

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2017, New Orleans, USA Wei Dai, Chia Dai, Shuhui Qu, **Juncheng Billy Li**, Samarjit Das

♦ A Comparison of Deep Learning Methods for Environmental Sound Detection

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2017, New Orleans, USA **Juncheng Billy Li**, Wei Dai, Florian Metze, Shuhui Qu, Samarjit Das

♦ Masked autoencoders that listen

NeurIPS 2022

Po-yao Huang, Hu Xu, **Juncheng B Li**, Alexei Baevski, Michael Auli, Wojciech Galuba, Florian Metze, Christoph Feichtenhofer

♦ Learning Joint Embedding of Video and Text for Cross-Modal Retrieval

International Conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR) 2018, Yokohama, Japan (BEST PAPER AWARD) Niluthpol Mithun, Juncheng B Li, Amit Roy-Chowdhury, Florian Metze

♦ Towards Zero-shot Learning for Automatic Phonemic Transcription

AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2020 (acceptance rate: 20.6%) , New York
Xinjian Li, Siddharth Dalmia, David R Mortensen, **Juncheng Li**, Alan W Black, Florian Metze

♦ A comparison of five multiple instance learning pooling functions for sound event detection with weak labeling

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2019, Brighton, UK Yun Wang, **Juncheng Li**, Florian Metze

♦ Multiple Instance Deep Learning for Weakly Supervised Small-Footprint Audio Event Detection
Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association 2018, India

Shaoyen Tseng, **Juncheng B Li,** Florian Metze, Joseph Szurley, Samarjit Das

 AudioTagging Done Right: 2nd comparison of deep learning methods for environmental sound classification

Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association 2022 **Juncheng B Li,** Shuhui Qu, Poyao Bernie Huang, Florian Metze

On Adversarial Robustness of Large-scale Audio Visual Learning
 ICASSP 2022, Singapore (BEST STUDENT PAPER AWARD)

Juncheng B Li, Shuhui Qu, Xinjian Li, Poyao Huang, Florian Metze

♦ Audio-visual event recognition through the lens of adversary

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2021, Online **Juncheng Li**, Kaixin Ma, Shuhui Qu, Po-Yao Huang, Florian Metze

♦ A Light-weight Multimodal Framework For Improved Environmental Audio Tagging

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) 2018, Calgary, Canada **Juncheng Li**, Yun Wang, Joseph Szurley, Florian Metze, Samarjit Das

Adversarial camera stickers: A physical camera-based attack on deep learning systems
International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML) 2019 (acceptance rate 21.8%), Long Beach, USA

♦ Universal phone recognition with a multilingual allophone system

Juncheng B Li, Frank R Schmidt, J Zico Kolter

IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing 2020, Online
Xinjian Li, Siddharth Dalmia, **Juncheng Li**, ..., Graham Neubig, Alan W Black, Florian Metze

♦ Music Theory Inspired Policy Gradient Method for Piano Music Transcription

Neural Information Process System 2018 Workshop on creativity AI, Montreal, Canada **Juncheng Li**, Shuhui Qu, Yun Wang, Xinjian Li, Samarjit Das, Florian Metze

♠ Adversarial Music: Real world Audio Adversary against Wake-word Detection System Neural Information Process Sysem (NeurIPS 2019), Vancouver, Canada (SpotLight, top 2.4%) Juncheng Li, Shuhui Qu, Xinjian Li, Joseph Szurley, Zico Kolter, Florian Metze